<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  	<Buildings>
		<Row>
			<Type>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</Type>
			<Description>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_DESC</Description>
			<Civilopedia>TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_TEXT</Civilopedia>
			<Strategy>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_STRATEGY</Strategy>
			<Help>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_HELP</Help>
			<GoldMaintenance>6</GoldMaintenance>
			<MutuallyExclusiveGroup>-1</MutuallyExclusiveGroup>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<HurryCostModifier>5</HurryCostModifier>
			<MinAreaSize>-1</MinAreaSize>
			<BuildingClass>BUILDINGCLASS_THEATRE</BuildingClass>
			<PrereqTech>TECH_SCIENTIFIC_THEORY</PrereqTech>
			<LandmarksTourismPercent>25</LandmarksTourismPercent>
			<PortraitIndex>2</PortraitIndex>
			<IconAtlas>CL_SOUTH_AFRICA_ATLAS</IconAtlas>
			<GrantsRandomResourceTerritory>1</GrantsRandomResourceTerritory>
			<UnculturedHappinessChange>-30</UnculturedHappinessChange>
		</Row>
 	</Buildings>
	<Building_ClassesNeededInCity>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</BuildingType>
			<BuildingClassType>BUILDINGCLASS_CIRCUS</BuildingClassType>
		</Row>
	</Building_ClassesNeededInCity>
	<Building_Flavors>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</BuildingType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_CULTURE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>90</Flavor>
		</Row>
	</Building_Flavors>
	<Building_InstantYield>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</BuildingType>
			<YieldType>YIELD_TOURISM</YieldType>
			<Yield>100</Yield>
		</Row>
	</Building_InstantYield>
	<Building_FeatureYieldChanges>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</BuildingType>
			<FeatureType>FEATURE_JUNGLE</FeatureType>
			<YieldType>YIELD_TOURISM</YieldType>
			<Yield>1</Yield>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</BuildingType>
			<FeatureType>FEATURE_FOREST</FeatureType>
			<YieldType>YIELD_TOURISM</YieldType>
			<Yield>1</Yield>
		</Row>
	</Building_FeatureYieldChanges>
	<Building_YieldChanges>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK</BuildingType>
			<YieldType>YIELD_CULTURE</YieldType>
			<Yield>2</Yield>
		</Row>
	</Building_YieldChanges>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_DESC">
			<Text>Safari Park</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_TEXT">
			<Text>Southern Africa is home to a myriad of national parks and marine protected areas managed by the national government, public nature reserves managed by provincial and local governments, and private nature reserves managed by private landowners. Most protected areas are intended for the conservation of flora and fauna. Although the term 'Safari Park' is also used to define a zoo-like commercial drive-in tourist attraction, the name is used to represent the vast multitude of protected biodiverse reserves spread throughout the region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unlike the Zoo, which it replaces, the Safari Park gains unique Resources ([ICON_RES_ZIM_RHINO] Rhino, [ICON_RES_ZIM_LION] Lion, and [ICON_RES_ZIM_SPRINGBOK] Springbok). These are all Monopolies and count towards Landsea Extractors.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZIM_SAFARI_PARK_HELP">
			<Text>Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Boredom. Nearby Jungle and Forest tiles gain +1 [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism. 25% of the [ICON_CULTURE] Culture from World Wonders, Natural Wonders, and Improvements is added to the [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism output of the city. Generates a unique Luxury Resource nearby.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_ZIM_LION">
			<Text>Lion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_ZIM_LION_TEXT">
			<Text>The Transvaal lion (Panthera leo krugeri), also known as the Southeast African lion or Kalahari lion inhabit the Transvaal region in South Africa. White lions (famous for their beauty the world over) are actually color mutation of the Transvaal lions. Transvaal lions live in the savannah, grasslands and semi-arid regions. The Transvaal lion is the southernmost subspecies of African lions, ranging from southern Namibia to southeastern Mozambique. There are more than 2000 lions of this subspecies in the well-protected Kruger National Park.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_ZIM_LION_HELP">
			<Text>Generated by a Zimbabwean unique building.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Monopoly Bonus:[ENDCOLOR] +2 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_ZIM_RHINO">
			<Text>Rhinoceros</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_ZIM_RHINO_TEXT">
			<Text>The black rhinoceros or hook-lipped rhinoceros is a species of rhinoceros, native to eastern and southern Africa. For most of the 20th century the continental black rhino was the most numerous of all rhino species. Around 1900 there were probably several hundred thousand living in Africa. Although rhinos are large and have a reputation for being tough, they are very easily poached; statistics from South African National Parks show that 333 rhinoceros were killed in South Africa in 2010, increasing to 668 by 2012, over 1,004 in 2013, and over 1,338 killed in 2015. In some cases rhinos are drugged and their horns removed, while in other instances more than the horn is taken.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_ZIM_RHINO_HELP">
			<Text>Generated by a Zimbabwean unique building.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Monopoly Bonus:[ENDCOLOR] +10% [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age Length.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_ZIM_SPRINGBOK">
			<Text>Springbok</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_ZIM_SPRINGBOK_TEXT">
			<Text>The springbok is a medium-sized antelope found mainly in southern and southwestern Africa. The springbok has been a national symbol of South Africa since the white minority rule in the 20th century. It was adopted as a nickname or mascot by several South African sports teams, most famously by the national rugby union team. The springbok is the national animal of South Africa. Even after the decline of apartheid, Nelson Mandela intervened to keep the name of the animal for the reconciliation of rugby fans, the majority of whom were whites.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_ZIM_SPRINGBOK_HELP">
			<Text>Generated by a Zimbabwean unique building.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Monopoly Bonus:[ENDCOLOR] +2 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science on tile.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
