<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/20/2013 3:43:32 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- UB -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MORI_LACE_MAKER">
			<Text>Lace Maker</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MORI_LACE_MAKER_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and [ICON_GOLD] Gold from all Forests and Marshes worked by this City. Allows [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to be moved from this city along trade routes inside your civilization.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Generates 1 [ICON_RES_MORI_LACE] Lace nearby.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MORI_LACE_MAKER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Continue to acquire luxuries as well as increase the number of tiles on which you may construct Bourg. By extending the Workshop's Forest bonuses to Marsh even more can be gained from Flander's Feature affinity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_MORI_LACE_MAKER_TEXT">
			<Text>The origin of lace is disputed by historians, with claims from both Flanders and Northern Italy - two regions which were in close contact - dating it to the end of the 15th century. The practice spread throughout the Low Countries where it became a large part of the economy, with many centres such as Brussels, Mechlin, Valenciennes and Binche giving their name to the local style. Lace making was a woman's job and would be done at home, providing them with economic freedom. The hand-made product was so costly that in 1662, the English Parliament passed an act prohibiting the import of all foreign lace, as it was alarmed at how much money was being spent on it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MORI_LACE">
			<Text>Lace</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_MORI_LACE_TEXT">
			<Text>Lace is a delicate fabric made of yarn or thread in an open weblike pattern. There are many types of lace, classified by how they are made. A famous style is Brussels lace, a type of pillow lace, which was started to be produced in the 15th century and is well known for its delicacy and beauty. Originally it was only made from the finest spun linen thread, which was spun in dark damp rooms to keep the thread from becoming too brittle. Only one ray of light was allowed into the room, and it was arranged so that it fell upon the thread. Brussels lace was extremely expensive but nevertheless in high demand in England and France.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MORI_LACE_HELP">
			<Text>Generated by a Flemish unique building. Provides no bonus while derelict.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Monopoly Bonus:[ENDCOLOR] +10% [ICON_GOLD] Gold in all owned Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>